School Entrance
Elementary School Entrance Ceremony
Done?
Well... yeah.
It's not clear at all.
Rin-chan! Kouki! Stand together.
OK~!
Kouki-kun.
Uhh...
Get ready!
Now, let's get one with just you and Rin-chan.
I don't need it.
Don't think like that!
Children grow up very quickly.
How could you not leave one for commemoration?
OK.
Daikichi-san, your expression is too stiff!
Osu Elementary School Entrance Ceremony
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことは　分かんない
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau nanika ga chigau
これって　犠牲とは違う　何かが違う
This is different from sacrificing, very different.
batsugeemu jaa nante omou wa nai
罰ゲームじゃあ　なんて思うわない
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
tte nande nanoka ha wakannai
って　なんでなのかは　分かんない
I can't really say well what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと　釈然としないけど
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nantemonjanai
キミの存在　今大事だ　なんてもんじゃない
but "important" cannot be used to describe your existence any more.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai
終わらないことなんて　この世のどこにもない
There's nothing that will last forever without coming to an end.
naku no ha tsurai janai no
泣くのは辛いじゃないの
Crying is a very painful thing
I know! Sweet drops! Sweet drops!
zutto yume mite itaine
ずっと　夢見ていたいね
I have always wanted to dream
motto yasashiku shitaine
もっと　優しくしたいね
To be able to be more gentle
kimi to iraretara happy!
キミと居られたら　happy!
Just being together with you is happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って　強いね
Girls are strong,
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど　時々　弱いね
but at times, they are weak.
bokura no negai ha happy! happy! happy...
僕らの願いは　happy! happy! happy...
Our wish is to be happy! Happy! Happy!
sonna hibi mo happy!
そんな日々も happy!
Such happy days!
Just wanna make you happy...
Wha...?! Damn it.
Hey, Rin!
Haven't I told you many times not to run off on your own?
Yes~
You're already a big sister, so be more serious.
"Yes~", stop that already.
Daikichi, can I buy this as a snack?
Snack!?
It looks really tasty.
Haven't you eaten any cereal before?
Yeah. Am I too old for this?
I could buy it if you want.
But this is for eating during breakfast.
What? You can eat snacks during meal times?
Wait... how do I put it?
It seems like a snack,
but it can be taken as a proper meal, if you pour some milk on it.
Really?
Eat it for breakfast tomorrow.
OK, I will.
Daikichi will have some too?
I'll pass.
It doesn't fill me up much.
Put the cereal inside this.
OK.
Daikichi is so useless.
My hands are very dry.
Just like an old man.
Shut up!
Oh! MitoKoumon.
Daikichi. There's some cherry blossoms, so let's go this way.
OK.
They're everywhere.
Because it's getting warm.
It's huge.
It's in full bloom.
Since you're already an elementary school student,
why not plant something as a form of commemoration?
Commemoration?
It means to keep the memory of something.
The tree and Rin will grow taller together every year.
I have a tree of my own, too.
At our place?
It's at my old home.
A Golden Osmanthus was planted when I was born.
A Silver Osmanthus was planted when Kazumi was born, though.
Is the Golden Osmanthus the one that's very fragrant?
Yeah, that's right.
I've never heard of the Silver Osmanthus.
Well, the smell and flowers of the Silver Osmanthus are very ordinary.
So Kazumi was always yelling, "How come only Onii-chan's flowers smell good? It's not fair!"
After that, she'd pluck the flowers on my Golden Osmanthus.
I suggested to swap with her.
But she said, "I don't want hand-me-downs!"
Strange? There's not a single fond memory at all.
Then why am I trying to do the same thing again?
Well, if you want to plant something, it's best to plant those that can bloom beautiful flowers.
Or bear fruits that can be eaten.
I want a Loquat!
Loquat?
Yeah, Loquat.
Loquat seeds. I've kept them.
You want to plant seeds?
I can eat Loquats any time.
That is, if they bloom properly.
Initially, I wanted to plant a sapling around the same height as you.
Loquat's no good?
The rate at which the tree grows is much slower compared to the Morning Glory or something.
It was from that saying,
Peach and chestnut seeds take three years to bear fruit...
Plums take eight years!
That's Grandpa's kid for you.
How about Loquats?
I don't really know.
But what happens if it takes ten years?
I can wait.
You'll probably be obsessed with desserts by then.
I can't even bear to think about it.
Daikichi, hurry!
It'll take a very long time before we can eat, if we don't plant it sooner.
Right away.
Is this deep enough?
Yeah, the shoot won't come out if it's too deep.
I see.
I was right to say that you're the old man's kid.
Wouldn't it be great if it can bloom faster?
Yeah.
Rin, do you know what a Ninja is?
Yeah, Kouki-kun said he wants to be a Ninja.
The ninjas have to jump over a tree called the Hemp everyday.
As the tree grows taller, the ninja will be able to jump extremely high.
Really?
You should practise with the Loquat, too.
I want to try it!
Just like that.
Like that?
Yes, yes.
Hey, how tall can Loquats grow?
Can it reach the roof of our house?
I don't know.
But it should be around there.
You should get inside already.
Then, ten more times.
Will it sprout tomorrow?
Tomorrow's a bit too soon.
Make sure you don't forget anything.
OK.
Our timetable.
The teacher told us to have someone at home take a look at it.
Man, what a bother.
I didn't have things like this when I was young.
It's really true.
There's even "please acknowledge" on it.
A fire?
Sounds like a patrol car.
An accident?
I'm not sure.
Daikichi, help me hook the whistle on the bag.
Rin.
When a stranger tries to talk to you, blow this with all your might.
OK.
Also, regardless of whose house it is, run into it immediately.
One more thing, a shop is fine too!
Yes!
Rin! School!
Daikichi, hurry and wake up.
I'm going to be late.
Yes.
Itadakimasu.
Itadakimasu!
You have to add some milk.
Can I just eat it like this a bit?
It's all right, if you want to.
Pet dogs eat these, don't they?
That's dog food; specially made just for dogs.
Is that so?
It is so!
People can't eat things that dogs eat.
Don't give that disappointed face.
Is it good?
Yeah, it's delicious.
But the best is still the Onigiri.
The Onigiri sure is incredible.
Daikichi's phone.
Coming.
Good morning!
I'm really sorry.
Kouki couldn't wait any longer, and ran off on his own.
No, it's fine. It's all right if he comes.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun is here.
He's here.
Hi.
Kouki-kun, you have burrs all over you.
Which monster-road did you take to get here?
I'm not a monster.
And also, what's with your head?
Bring a comb here, Rin.
Yes~!
Seriously, there are scratches on your backpack.
That piece of stick you're holding,
I'm sure you were dragging it against the walls of others on the way.
Are you a psychic?
You can tell from one look, since it's so obvious.
Daikichi must have done it in the past, too.
Rin, you hurry up and get ready.
Yes~!
What's with that stare of yours?
I'm going off!
Hey, wait a second.
I'll see you off.
What's wrong?!
Kouki-kun! You can't blow the whistle as and when you like!
Kouki-kun!
Hey!
What are you blowing that much for?!
No one will save you if you really get into trouble!
Do you understand?
Yeah.
Well then, you two should get going.
We're going now!
Watch out for cars!
Yes~!
Kouki-kun.
Let's go this way.
We should go straight to school.
We will, it's a shortcut.
A real ninja... walks this sort of path.
Jeez...
Wow, it's an curvy side road.
Told you.
Kouki-kun, you're so slow!
This isn't even a shortcut.
You don't blow that!
Kouki-kun!
There's really no helping that kid.
Isn't that right.
Well, about that, boys are normally like that.
Daikichi!
But a ninja's practise is only jumping the Loquat.
Yep!
Erm, that Loquat is a memento of entering school, right?
Yeah.
But your Golden Osmanthus is to commemorate your birth,
so it's slightly different from mine.
Isn't there a Golden Osmanthus or something that belongs to me?
You're really intelligent.
Does that mother look like someone who would plant a tree?
Is it over at Grandpa's place?
That's right.
Grandpa probably would have planted it.
But you don't know whether there's any, right?
Yeah.
Grandpa is no longer around.
If I don't know, there's no way anyone else would.
I shouldn't have brought up the Golden Osmanthus matter.
Daikichi! You're resting your elbows on the table again!
Oh, yeah, sorry.
Damn it.
I thought we wouldn't be meeting ever again?
I should be the one telling you that.
This was taken during the entrance ceremony.
Thank you.
What? Rin's tree?
Ah, yes! There is one!
There is?
Well, I mean... I think there is.
You don't even know if there is one?
Souichi-san was the one who planted it.
Grandpa?
I want to move that tree over to my place.
What kind of tree is that?
It's a small tree.
Well, I want to know what type of tree it is.
As well as where it is.
The tree was still really small, and the branches also very thin.
It's here.
I recall you're a manga artist?
But I don't draw maps for a living.
Which direction is north?
North?
The sun rises from the west-
It's the reverse! That song is reversed.
Forget about the direction.
Can you draw the way from the front of the house?
Ah, yeah. You're right.
Well then, I'll be leaving first, since I still have work to do.
Thank you for your time.
Thank you for taking time out of your busy schedule.
Was it planted... my own tree?
I'm sure Grandpa planted something for you.
I have a good feeling about this.
Even if there isn't one, it's fine if you just plant another tree to commemorate your entrance ceremony.
Plant a six-year-old tree.
OK.
Do you want to take a look at Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I want to see!
Wow, it's so big!
That's because it's already thirty years old, same as Daikichi.
It's tall, just like Daikichi.
It's called a Golden Osmanthus, right?
That's right. You know quite a lot.
Daikichi told me.
This one over here is Kazumi's tree.
Silver Osmanthus?
Correct.
Do you remember the huge tree in the backyard of Grandpa's house?
Ah, that one?
That tree belongs to me; it's a Silver Osmanthus.
Oh? This tree.
Grandpa planted this for me when I was born.
Aunty and Kazumi Onee-chan are the same.
That's right.
I always compared my height with the tree's when I was young.
I loved it a lot back then.
So I planted the same tree for Kazumi.
I see, that tree is a Silver Osmanthus.
Did Daikichi also compare his height?
Of course.
Much earlier than before that day we met...
That you're holding is?
The same kind of leaves.
A six-year-old Golden Osmanthus, the same tree as mine.
It'll be completed like this.
Oh no.
What is it?
I can't jump over this.
Even I can't jump over it.
Until half a year ago, I didn't even know that Rin existed.
Yeah.
Daikichi! The train will leave soon!
Coming!
See you.
I'll see both of you out.
But, even far before that...
You were already walking on the same path as us.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Daikichi!
What happened!?
Did something happen?!
There's a weird uncle outside.
What did you say?
No... The person is...
Where is that uncle?
Daikichi, that's not it.
HEY! Both of you listen to me!
That's Matsui-san from next door.
Don't say he's a weird uncle!
I'm really sorry about that.
I-am-sor-ry.
It's all right.
I must have frightened them by suddenly speaking to them.
I'm sorry.
No, we should apologise instead.
It was very rude of us.
Well then, you two have a safe trip to school.
We'll be going now~!
Thank you.
You grabbed Rin and took her along when you escaped.
What? Kouki-kun obviously made a mistake.
I'm slightly at ease having Kouki with you.
Only slightly?!
Yeah, only slightly!
You're still an imp.
I'm not an imp!
We're going to be late.